## Joel Amos Adero

# Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer

amosjoel91@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/joel-amos Github: github.com/Murzuqisah|Portfolio: joel-portfolio-joel-amos.vercel.app/ Address: Kisumu, Nyanza, 10, Kenya | Phone: +254716919392

#### **Profile Summary**

Experienced full-stack developer and cybersecurity expert in network security, risk assessment, and threat mitigation. Credible in leading security audits, implementing secure architectures, and ensuring regulatory compliance. Strong transferable skills in incident response, cloud security, and cross-functional collaboration to enhance cybersecurity resilience.

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming & Scripting: PHP, JavaScript, Go, NodeJS, Solidity, Bash, ReactJS, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

Web, Data Analysis & Responsive Web Design: HTML, SCSS, SQLite3, JSON, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Figma, Canva, Bootstrap

APIs & Microservices: RESTful APIs, Docker, Kubernetes

**Version Control:** Git, GitLab, GitHub **Project Management:** Trello, Slack

Software Development: Full-Stack Development, Responsive Web Design, Agile Methodologies

## Work Experience

Software Developer Apr 2024 - Present

Zone01 Kisumu | Kisumu County, Kenya

- Implemented blockchain-based secure payment transactions, reducing fraudulent transactions by 45%.
- Developed an optimized decision tree-based AI model (c4.5) for text indexing, enhancing query performance by 35%.
- Built and secured a forum application for tech discussions, implementing robust authentication and encryption, reducing unauthorized access attempts by 50%.

Mentor Feb 2023 - Aug 2023

Young Scientists Kenya | Concern Worldwide Offices, Ariel House, Westlands Avenue, Nairobi, Kenya

- I trained 100+ high school students in Scratch programming, improving their understanding of coding fundamentals and computational thinking.
- I designed and delivered 50+ interactive lessons, enhancing creativity and problem-solving skills in students.
- I developed hands-on projects that increased student engagement by 70%, making programming more accessible and enjoyable.

#### **Education**

Maseno University Sep 2022 - Dec 2024

**Diploma** Information Technology

Courses: Network Design and Analysis, Data Structures and Algorithms, Basic Programming, Applied Mathematics

**GPA**: Distinction

**Eldoret National Polytechnic** 

Sep 2017 - Nov 2020

**Diploma** Biomedical Engineering

Courses: Hospital Engineering, Medical Electronics, Engineering Mathematics

GPA: Credit

#### Referees

Mr. Bryant Khamunde

IT Consultant

Kitengela International Schools PLC(KISC PLC)

Email: khamundebryant@gmail.com

+254724 352921

Mr. Newton Omondi

Lecturer

Maseno University

Email: nomondis@gmail.com

+254727 776234

Reverend Philemon Owino Oguna

Priest

Anglican Church of Kenya Diocese of Maseno South

Email: owinoguna@gmail.com

+254748 405003